Sub agents are one of the most powerful
capabilities inside of Claw Code. And
while a lot of people, a lot of creators
talk about them or cover them, nobody is
showing you how to build sub agents for
writing operations or content creation
inside of Cloud Code. So that's what I'm
going to do today. I'm going to show you
exactly how you can build a writing
agent, how you can give it access to
Claude skills to use, and how you can
implement all of this in a larger
writing system inside of Claude Code.
Make sure to watch to the end of the
video if you want to use all the exact
resources I show you in this video. I'll
tell you exactly how you can get them
and put them into your own Claude code
system. Before we get started into it,
let's first just define what sub agents
are. And to do that, we'll just look at
Claude Codes documentation because they
can define it better than any of us can.
These are specialized AI sub aents in
Cloud Code for task specific workflows
and improved context management. custom
sub aents in cloud code or special AI
assistance that can be invoked to handle
specific types of tasks. Now also
important to note you don't even have to
manually invoke these. If you have
effective claude.md system prompts, if
you have effective sub aent system
prompts, then it will autonomously
invoke the agents uh you know when it
should. So that is another uh important
thing to keep in mind. You can basically
build out teams of these sub aents
inside of your cloud code writing system
and just run all these different writing
operations, you know, with spinning up
sub aents simultaneously, invoking them
autonomously. So, there are a couple key
benefits, you know, that we can run
through really quick of sub agents. The
first is context preservation. Each
operates in its own context. This means
it doesn't pollute the main
conversation. It stays inside of that
context. It also allows you to give
specialized expertise to these sub
agents so they can be fine-tuned with
detailed instructions. Now, people
create agents, you know, in various
different ways. You know, a lot of what
you're going to see out there is for
development and coding work. But what I
find best for writing operations in
content creation is specifically using
these sub agents as more or less like
orchestrator agents for specific tasks.
And then what you can do is load those
sub aents up with specific claude skills
that teach them how to carry out a
specific task like writing a newsletter
or a thought leadership article or maybe
social media posts and the list can go
on and on. So what you really want is
these sub agents to be like
orchestrators and then have a library of
skills that they can invoke under them
to carry out specific writing or content
tasks. Also reusability once created you
can use them across different projects.
You could copy and paste these agents.
You could sell them. You can use them in
client systems. All of that is possible.
And then we have flexible permissions.
Each one can have different access to
different tools, which we'll see when we
actually create it. Now, to create this
on the left side of my screen, you're
going to see I have Claude code running
in the terminal. I'm using cursor, but
you could be using any, you know, code
editor tool that that you want. You can
also even use Claude's own desktop app,
which now has Claude code in it. And you
can even use a VS Code extension so you
could see all of your different folders.
And then my writing system here, we have
a Claude file with an agents folder in a
skills folder. We have a context file or
context folder with my JSON context
profiles which explain to Claude, you
know, in JSON about my business about my
ideal client profiles and how to write
in my voice DNA. Then we have a
knowledge folder which I use to hold uh
you know all the different you know
drafts and knowledge of my writing
operations. And then we have our
claude.md
system prompt. Now you can have you know
whatever system that you're running
inside of claude code but you can also
get this exact starting kit folder. I'm
calling this like a claude code starter
kit and you can watch my master class
here that's also on YouTube and get
access to this starter kit that you can
just uh put right open up right in your
own cursor or claude code and use it.
But either way works. Today we're going
to be just putting an agent inside of
this system. Okay. So what we're going
to do I'm going to open up the terminal
here and to create an agent the first
thing we need to do is put slash agent.
And this is going to allow us to manage
our agent configurations. You can see I
already have one here that I created
which we are going to delete really
quick so that we could start fresh. But
you're going to see all right agents. No
agents found. Now we can create
specialized sub agents. Now there are a
couple built-in agents that you might
not even have realized using cloud code.
These are the ones that cloud code
itself uses the ones that are like
automatically inside here. There's like
a general purpose one, a planning one,
but today we're going to create specific
ones for writing. So you're just going
to hit enter here. And then the first
thing you need to do is choose your
location. You can either choose project
meaning it's inside this project here or
personal meaning it's on your system
file or locally across all your
projects. For writing operations, I like
highly recommend using project specific
agents because it's super easy just to
take that file, copy it and paste it
into any other projects and keep
everything nice and clean. Especially if
you're dealing, for example, maybe
you're a ghostriter dealing with
multiple clients or maybe you're running
content for different startups or
businesses or CEOs or whatever. I like
to keep everything very siloed and
protected from one another. So, I always
use project here. The next we're going
to have to do is choose our generation
method. We can either generate with
Claude or we can do a manual
configuration. If you hit enter on
generate with Claude, all you have to do
is explain what kind of agent you want
very simply. Be as detailed as possible,
and Claude will create it for you. But
for today, that's not what we're going
to do. We're going to do a manual
configuration because I highly recommend
you just get good at writing these
system prompts or finding other people
like myself who provide them to you
because these are highly specific for
writing operations. These are the ones
we use, I use in my daily uh, you know,
writing businesses and content
businesses. So, we're going to hit enter
on manual configuration. And the first
thing we need to do is enter a unique
identifier. Today, what we're going to
build is a newsletter uh writing agent.
So, we're going to say a newsletter
writer or we'll just say a newsletter
agent. Click enter. Now, we need to
write the system prompt. Now, there are
many many techniques to go into writing
system prompts. You can go learn those.
You can study those. You can try it out
yourself. I highly recommend always
doing it. I don't write system prompts
from scratch either. I work with Claude
to write system prompts. Oftentimes what
I'll do is also, you know, prior to this
whole, you know, new Claude code and
agents and all these different, you
know, ways to run your writing
operations. A lot of a lot of what we
were using were prompts, right? Very
detailed prompts beforehand. You can
take those prompts and they are amazing
starting points for building out into
full agent system prompts. So, if you
have prompts that you really like or
that you've been using, just give that
to Claude and ask it to help you turn
that into an agent system prompt. Uh,
and then go from there. Here, what we're
going to do is I already have one. We're
going to come here to my resources for
my Subscribers.
So, if you want this exact uh these
exact agent system prompts and various
other tools and skills, uh, check out my
Substack. That's where you can get it.
But we have the newsletter writer agent
here and I have written out the entire
system prompt. So we got the name like I
said and now here is the system prompt.
Claude code agents or sub aents all
they're using is an MD you know a
markdown file for the system prompt. So
you can literally just copy this here.
We have a newsletter writer agent. I'm
going to copy all of this and then we'll
go through it and I'll read you through
some of it so you can see kind of how
this works. Okay. So here on the left
now we have the system prompt.
Newsletter writer agent. You are a
newsletter writing specialist. Your job
is to coordinate the production of
complete ready to publish newsletters.
We then tell it that it's not writing
from scratch. What it needs to do is
load the user's context profiles from
our system here on the left. It needs to
gather necessary information from the
user, find and use the appropriate
writing skill. Like I told you, I build
my agents so they invoke Claude skills.
One of the most incredible things about
Claude Code now is we have all these
tools at our disposal. We have the sub
agents, you know, or the cloud. MD at
the top. We have sub agents underneath
that. We have library of cloud skills
underneath that. We have MCP servers.
There's so much we can do for writing
operations. Like nobody is doing this.
So, if you're watching this video right
now, if you're following me, if you're
even attempting to start building this
out, you are like in the 1% of the 1% of
people using AI for writing operations
because nobody else is really doing this
right now. And then it's going to
deliver a complete newsletter. We go
through the step-by-step process. We
tell it what to do and what not to do.
All right. After we have the system
prompts, we're just going to hit enter
here. And now we're going to give it a
description. This description is what
your your main claude is going to read
to know like when and when to use or
invoke this agent. I actually have this
written here too. So, let me just grab
that also and copy it. We're going to
tell it here in its description. We're
going to say writes complete newsletters
using context profiles and available
skills. Use when a user wants to write
Substack newsletters. You can change
this to just uh you know thought
leadership newsletters or just regular
newsletters. Like I said, I have
Substack. So I use this for myself for
my own Substack uh content. And then
we'll say mentions write a newsletter or
draft a newsletter or needs long form
educational content for their audience.
So this just helps Claude understand
when to use it. We're going to hit
enter. Now we can select the tools we
want to give it access to. We want to
give it access to all the tools here.
But you can even open this up and and
take away or give certain access to
certain tools. We're going to give it
access to all tools. And now we need to
select the model. If you do writing
operations at scale, if you're serious
about writing with AI in any level, if
you're actually using it for
professional work, highly recommend you
sign up for Claude's uh or Anthropics
Claude Max plan. Anywhere between a
hundred I think to $200 a month, right?
I use the $200 a month plan and I run
Opus like multiple hours a day all day
long. I never run into limits. So, if
that's what you have, I recommend using
Opus, uh, you know, as much as you can.
Then, we're just going to choose a color
here for the agent, whatever. Automatic
color. And this is our new agent. We can
now enter to save it. And there it is.
We now have the agent, newsletter agent.
And you're going to see that now in this
dotcloud file, we have agents and we
have our newsletter agent right here. So
it's as simple as that. That's how we
build the agent. But we're not done yet,
right? Because yeah, the agents there,
but it has no skills. This is like a
agent with no skills. So we need to give
it skills. And the skill we're going to
give it, which it should eventually
have, you know, many skills at its
disposal to, you know, invoke. But what
I want to give it is a thought
leadership newsletter skill. All right.
Also, I'm going to include this for
subsec members. If you want, you can
just download and use this exact claude
skill. You could or you can go look for
your own skills. You know, if you have
them already, there's libraries out
there. You could try to find them. But I
really like this thought leadership
newsletter skill. I use it for myself,
for clients. Uh you can use it for, you
know, writing thought leadership for
executives, CEOs, startups, for
yourself, for industry leaders. And what
this newsletter skill does is it writes
valuep packed thought leadership
newsletters between 800 to 1500 words
that educate, entertain, and position
the writer as the go-to authority in
their space. We're going to tell it when
to activate this. When a user wants to
write a newsletter weekly email, we're
going to give it a core philosophy. Now,
this is very detailed skill. My claude
skills are highly detailed, multiple
pages long. Uh so we have the four
pillars of a killer newsletter. We tell
it, you know, how to load our contact
profiles. Kind of everything you see
that I built here is very specific to
our system. So this is not something
other people are going to be copying and
using. We have a very uh very unique
approach here to building out writing
operations inside of Cloud Code. We're
going to tell it to load the context
profiles, craft subject lines, uh what
else? Write these hooks, greetings, all
right, CTAs, all of that. It goes on and
on and on, right? Not going to read
through all of it. But once you have
this skill, which you can literally
download if you want the zip file here,
and then we'll have the down here in the
downloads, that will give us this folder
here. And this is already in the correct
format for Claude skills, which is the
skill.md file in folder. And we just are
going to drag that into our skills,
which I already have there. So just
replace it. And now you could see we
have my agents folder with my newsletter
agent and my skills folder with a couple
skills that are already there and then
this new thought leadership skill. So
now we're officially done pretty much.
Now we have our our writing sub agent
inside of Claude Code for newsletters
and we have a thought leadership
newsletter skill that we're going to
give that agent access to. So the next
thing we do is just go to a regular
chat. And now this would be up to you,
you know, however it is you want to
write these. Say you are working for a
company or you are a ghostwriter for
CEOs or executives and you need to write
a thought leadership newsletter. You
just need to provide your notes or
transcripts or whatever serves as the
basis of your idea for the newsletter.
You're going to give it to Claude and
tell it to write a thought leadership
newsletter. Just to demonstrate this
quickly, I'll go to a YouTube video that
I released last week on adding 16
professional skills to your Cloud Code
setup. And I'm literally just going to
paste this transcript in here. And I'm
going to, you know, use voice dictation
to tell Claude, um, here is a transcript
on a YouTube video I did last week on
adding professional skills to your
Claude code setup. I want you to write a
thought leadership newsletter, uh, based
on this.
And then we're going to paste it. Paste
the transcript. Now when Claude starts
spinning up this process here, the first
thing it's going to do is read our
context profiles here, our JSON context
profiles. This is going to help it
understand our business or voice our
ideal client profiles. Uh so we want to
do that that is written into our claude
file or claude.md that is written into
our agents. Our skills all very heavily
rely on these context profiles. After
that, it's going to launch the
newsletter agent to write this thought
leadership newsletter based on my
YouTube video. So, that's going to take
a few seconds. I'll let that run
through. It's going to invoke the
thought leadership skill and uh and then
we'll see what the final output is. Now,
when you see this here, you could see
that this is the actual agent. Where did
it go? Here. This is the actual agent
that's spinning up and working here. And
we can even run this now in the
background. If you were to hit control
uh B, you could run this in the
background as you're doing other things
inside of Cloud Code, which is awesome.
You can run up multiple agents. You can
work on something else while it's
running. Uh but, you know, that's that's
for a future another video after you
start using uh agents. So, let's let
that run for a few seconds and then get
back to it. All right. So, it literally
took like less than a minute and it's
already done. We can see here that it
finished. The newsletter agent finished
and it gave us our thought leadership
newsletter based on the YouTube video.
It gives us our subject line options. We
have Claude Code has a secret upgrade
most people don't know about. I just
discovered hidden skills inside of Cloud
Code. The Claude feature that turns your
writing system into a content machine.
This is all based off of the skill I
gave it. We have the newsletter,
you know, this the thought leadership
newsletter completely written out in my
voice using my voice DNA targeted at my
ICP. uh you know at my ideal client
profile with my business context with
best practices for writing subject lines
and and and headings and titles with the
CTA that we told it. So we have this
very detailed thought leadership
newsletter. Uh and then we have a couple
notes here at the bottom. We sign off
here. Talk soon Alex. Then we have some
notes from Claude itself uh about what
it did here. So you can see like the
newsletter uses your voice DNA uh speaks
to your ICP's pain points and transform
transforms it into a scannable thought
leadership piece with clear CTAs. So
that is it. That is how you build out an
incredible writing operation inside of
Claude code. That is how you build a
newsletter writing sub agent with you
know Claude skills that it can use to
write different types of newsletters.
What I'm showing you here is incredibly
valuable. Uh this is just the beginning
of what you can do. Imagine all the
different sub aents you could build, all
the different cloud skills that you
could give them access to. And you start
to really see what the future of, you
know, writing operations inside of
Claude code or AI really looks like. You
see how much power one individual can
have with all these different sub aents
running underneath them, which is
exactly what I do. I don't have a single
employee. I don't have a single person
writing for me. I don't have nothing. I
run all of these writing operations and
agents myself in claude code across
different businesses. I have number two
newsletter rising on substack technology
that I use these sub agents to help me
with. I have client work. I ghostrite
for CEOs. I run content for startups all
by myself using these sub agents. So
definitely check this out. If you're not
doing it, you need to be doing it. And
if you haven't joined my substack yet,
definitely consider doing that because
here you'll get access to all these
resources that you see in my videos.
Quad code starting kits, quad code sub
agent skills. So check that out.